<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MSDS_Module-1_ChatGPT_Integration-Translator.ipynb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/github-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/github-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📘 &lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This project demonstrates a modular approach to building a multilingual translator using the LangChain framework and OpenAI’s GPT-4o-mini model. Designed for the MSDS 442 course at Northwestern University, this script showcases secure API integration, prompt engineering, and real-time language translation using large language models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🔧 &lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Environment Setup&lt;/strong&gt;: Uses &lt;code&gt;os&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;getpass&lt;/code&gt; to securely handle API keys for OpenAI, LangChain, and Tavily, avoiding hard-coded credentials.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LLM Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Initializes a GPT-4o-mini chat model via LangChain’s &lt;code&gt;ChatOpenAI&lt;/code&gt; class for efficient, conversational interactions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prompt Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;: Dynamically constructs system and user prompts using LangChain’s &lt;code&gt;PromptTemplate&lt;/code&gt;, guiding the model to translate text between languages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Workflow&lt;/strong&gt;: Accepts user-defined languages and phrases, fills the prompt templates with actual values, and invokes the model.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clear Output&lt;/strong&gt;: Displays both the final prompt structure and the model’s translation, providing full transparency into the LLM interaction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Dbalette/MSDS_Class_Work&#34;&gt;View the source code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my portfolio site! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is where I’ll be posting my projects as well as info &amp;amp; resources for the Northwestern MSDS community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sps.northwestern.edu/masters/data-science/&#34;&gt;https://sps.northwestern.edu/masters/data-science/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m currently pursuing a Master of Science in Data Science at Northwestern University 🎓&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My focus is on integrating data science, finance, and AI to solve complex problems and drive strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before Northwestern, I earned a Master’s in Accounting from the Carlson School of Management at the University of Minnesota, and a Bachelor of Science in Accounting from the University of Nebraska–Lincoln. I’ve held finance leadership roles across multiple companies, including as a Finance Manager, where I built a foundation in strategic decision-making and cross-functional collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-courses-ive-taken&#34;&gt;📚 Courses I&amp;rsquo;ve Taken&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a selection of graduate-level courses I’ve completed as part of the Master of Science in Data Science program at Northwestern University. Each course has played a role in building my expertise in data science, AI, and analytics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;msds-442-dl-ai-agent-design-and-development&#34;&gt;MSDS 442-DL: AI Agent Design and Development&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This applied AI course explores how to design, build, and deploy intelligent agents. Topics include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reason-and-act methods&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finite state machines and agent architectures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intelligent prompting and goal-driven systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Human-in-the-loop workflows&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;API integration and tool use&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Multi-agent systems with large language models&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course is project-based and involves using open-source frameworks to build stateful, autonomous agents capable of completing complex, multi-step tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
